**Q** Eagle, Idaho 83616 (flexible)

hello@matthewpenkala.com

**+**1 (916) 292-1643



MOTION DESIGN ARTIST VISUAL EFFECTS GENERALIST

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motion Design Artist & Visual Effects Generalist with 7+ years of experience. Transformed BlackBerry® Enterprises' identity via motion design for a B2B-relevant landscape. Strong leader with a result-oriented mindset. Known for creative solutions that captivate audiences and elevate brand presence.

#### INDUSTRY & WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - PRESENT /VARIOUS LOCATIONS /

## Freelance VFX/GFX Generalist, Upwork Global Inc. REMOTE

- · Collaborate with frequent clients to develop professional animations that enhance their projects and meet their specifications
- · Produce high-quality motion graphics for a diverse clientele, and meet various deadlines & budget constraints
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams, while contributing creative insights and adapting to evolving project
- · Manage multiple concurrent projects, ensuring client satisfaction and repeat business

2020 - 2022 LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA

## Lead Motion Graphics Artist, Unified Digital Design Associates REMOTE

- · Developed innovative & creative motion graphics and visual effects to enhance visual storytelling for highprofile clients (e.g., SAP®)
- · Collaborated with the creative team to develop concepts and storyboards for animated ad campaigns
- · Managed and mentored a temp. team of post-production artists to ensure consistent quality and timely delivery of projects

2016 - 2019 ROSEVILLE, CALIFORNIA

## Asst. Technical Director & Motion Designer, Bayside Church ON-SITE

- · Coordinated video production for live events with industry professionals, handling LED wall GFX content and directing video switching
- Produced engaging & high-energy lyric videos, showcasing mastery of Adobe After Effects to achieve outstanding
- · Worked closely with senior leadership to provide effective assistance for specific aspects of creative operation

2015 - 2017 GRANITE BAY, CALIFORNIA

# Digital Imaging Specialist, J. Fitzpatrick Art Collection ON-SITE

- · Developed & implemented (principally using Adobe Photoshop) effective digital imaging techniques to enhance the quality, yet preserve the integrity of hand-drawn artworks in the collection
- Collaborated with Jim Fitzpatrick to understand his vision and ensure digital manipulation strategies align with the artistic intent

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

AUG, 2016 - DEC, 2019

#### Graduation Diploma, Granite Bay High School, CA

Completed education with AP credits and a department award & phenomenal review from media/film director

## FIELD CERTIFICATIONS

#### Professional in VFX & Motion Graphics (After Effects)

ADOBE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL | PEARSON

<u>This certification</u> indicates industry-recognized expertise in Adobe After Effects, demonstrating a deep comprehension of key concepts and the program's interface for creating motion graphics and visual effects.

#### Professional in Comprehensive Video Design

ADOBE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL | PEARSON

The <u>'Video Design' certification</u> validates expertise in Adobe Creative Cloud software for creating & editing videos, requiring nuanced proficiency in at least 2 applications.

#### Professional in Digital Video (Premiere Pro)

ADOBE CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL | PEARSON

<u>This certification</u> illustrates advanced proficiency in Adobe Premiere Pro, with a thorough understanding of the program's video editing & exporting capabilities and competent knowledge of industry concepts.

## **SKILL SET & PROFICIENCIES**

Adobe After Effects	Motion Graphics / 2D Animation
Project Management	Visual Effects & Post-Production

## ADDITIONAL LINKS/URLS

Video Reel ☐ Portfolio (2023) ☐

LinkedIn Profile 🗹 Notable Clients 🗹